But not all dogs stay there!
All Dogs Go to Heaven is a drama, animation, family film directed by Don Bluth.
When a casino-owning dog named Charlie is murdered by his rival Carface, he finds
himself in Heaven basically by default since all dogs go to heaven.
However, since he wants to get back at his killer, he cons his way back to
the living with the warning that doing that damns him to Hell.
Once back, he teams with his old partner, Itchy, to prep his retaliation.
He also stumbles onto an orphan girl who can talk to the animals, thus allowing him to
get the inside info on the races to ensure his wins to finance his plans.
However, all the while, he is still haunted by nightmares of what's waiting for him on
the other side unless he can prove that he is worthy of Heaven again.
Charlie B. Barkin (voice), played by Burt Reynolds.
Itchy Itchiford (voice), played by Dom DeLuise.
Anne-Marie (voice), played by Judith Barsi.
Carface (voice), played by Vic Tayback.
Whippet Angel (voice), played by Melba Moore.
King Gator (voice), played by Ken Page.
All Dogs Go to Heaven is a 1989 animated musical fantasy comedy drama film directed by Don
Bluth and co-directed by Gary Goldman (his directorial debut) and Dan Kuenster.
Set in New Orleans in 1939, it tells the story of Charlie B.
Barkin (voiced by Burt Reynolds), a German Shepherd mix who is murdered by
his former friend, Carface Carruthers (voiced by Vic Tayback).
Charlie escapes from Heaven to return to Earth where his best friend, Itchy Itchiford
(voiced by Dom DeLuise), still lives, in order to take revenge on Carface.
Instead, he ends up befriending a young orphan girl named
Anne-Marie (voiced by Judith Barsi in her final film role).
In the process, Charlie learns an important lesson
about kindness, friendship and love.
The film is an Irish, British and American venture, produced by
Goldcrest Films and Sullivan Bluth Studios Ireland Limited.
On its cinema release, it competed directly with Walt Disney Feature
Animation's The Little Mermaid, released on the same day.
While it did not repeat the box-office success of Sullivan Bluth's previous features, An American Tail and The Land
Before Time, it was successful on home video, becoming one of the biggest-selling VHS releases ever.
It was followed by a theatrical sequel, a television
series, and a holiday direct-to-video film.
The film explores themes of new orleans, louisiana,
villain, heaven, little girl, dog.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.